2030年孩子们 咱都知道你们Barney叔就是个狗男人 (dog在俚语中指喜欢到处一夜情的男人)
Kids, it's no secret your Uncle Barney is a bit of a dog,
尽管他很爱我 但我一直觉得
and even though he loved me, I think he always wanted
他想找另一个狗男人作泡钮搭档
a wingman who was a bit of a dog, too.
在2012年的秋天
And in the fall of 2012...
他找到了
...he found one.
肃然起敬
Respect.
Respect
嘿 伙计们 昨晚很开心 谢谢你们
Hey, guys, thanks again for a great night last night.
我再说一次
I say again,
昨晚很开心
great night.
Ted 亲爱的 也没那么开心吧
Ted, honey, it was not a great night.
Ted 我和Lily昨晚注意到一些事
Ted, Lily and I noticed some things last night.
嘿 Ted 能帮我拿块饼乾吗
Hey, Ted, can you pass me a cracker?
我都为你逃婚了 你为我做这点事情总可以的吧
Yeah. It's the least you can do, considering I left a guy at the altar for you.
看这张嘴
Right, right?
拜托 那就是个玩笑话
Oh, come on, that was a joke.
过了30的女人 不拿婚姻大事开玩笑
Women over 30 don't joke when it comes to commitment.
Victoria希望我们能慢慢来
Victoria is happy we're taking things slow.
哦我的小宝贝 没有哪个32岁的女人
Oh, oh, honeysweetiebaby, no 32-year-old woman
会愿意慢慢来
is happy taking things slow.
相信我 Victoria的高中同学肯定 已经在脸书上贴了第二胎的照片
Trust me, Victoria has got friends from high school posting pictures of second babies on Facebook.
你以为她会"咱们就这么啪啪啪
And you think girlfriend's all like, "Oh, let's just bone a bunch
到明年我又老一岁还依旧未婚"吗
so I'm another year older and still single"?
贱人 你用用脑子
Bitch, please. Mm.
同志们 我有新哥们儿了
Guys, I've got a new bro-
一个足以让所有兄弟黯然失色的哥们
a bro that puts all other bros to shame.
小钮儿都喜欢他
The bitches love him.
他这一天都"精疲力尽"了 (字面意思:他这一天都在埋骨头)
He buries bones all day.
- 没人比他更会勾搭小钮了(字面:追尾巴) - 你们为什么不笑
No one chases tail like him. Why aren't you guys laughing?
哦对 我应该先说这句 他是只狗
Oh, wait, I probably should have led with this: he's a dog.
我给他取名
I've named him
流浪兄弟
Brover.
我这就去...
I'll go...
接应他
...fetch him.
好吧 我挺担心Barney的
Okay, I'm worried about Barney.
和Quinn分手对他造成的伤害远不止表面这些
That breakup with Quinn messed him up more than he let on.
- 他肯定很孤单 - 我看那小子挺好的啊
I think he's lonely. Dude seems fine to me.
我好爱你哦 流浪兄弟
I love you so much, Brover.
说真的 看昨晚的情况
Seriously, based on last night,
你和Victoria出问题了
you and Victoria are headed for trouble.
有人请我去丹佛经营一家蛋糕店
So I got this kind of interesting job offer to run a bakery in Denver.
这也太夸张了 是吧
But that's too crazy, though, right?
- 是吧 - 是啊
Right? Uh, yeah.
那么高的海拔会影响糕点的密度吧
The high altitude would affect the density of the pastries.
都烤得半生不熟的
I mean, talk about half-baked.
今晚可真开心啊
Man, this is a great night.
Victoria是在问你愿不愿意跟她搬去丹佛
That was Victoria asking you to move to Denver with her.
什么
What?
那她干嘛不直接说呢
Then, why wouldn't she just come right out and say what she wants?
男人啊
Men.
除了拧开泡菜子 打死蜘蛛
It's like, if there weren't pickle jars to open and spiders to kill
给电脑备份 他们还会干啥
and computers to back up, what would be their point?
Marshall什么时候变得比你还娘们儿了
Okay, when did Marshall become a slightly more feminine you?
听我说 Ted 总是给别人提建议
Look, Ted, it gets exhausting constantly giving people
人家还不领情 很累知道不 所以我要训练Marshall
advice they haven't asked for, so I'm training Marshall.
我的目标就是 让自己说出来的话
My goal is to eventually say things
显得好听又智慧
that are so sassy and wise,
让听的人只能说"嗯 没错"
that there is no possible response other than "mm" or "mm-hmm. "
要说我有什么梦想的话
And if this is a place where we can share our dreams-
那就是
I like to think that it is-
我希望有一天能够得到一句...
I hope someday to earn a...
出徒了
"testify. "
听著 我和Victoria在一起五个月 我们现在很好
Look, Victoria and I are five months in and we're right where we should be.
我们一起署名生日卡
All right, we-we're cosigning birthday cards,
在对方家里都有牙刷 在窗外搞前戏
w- we got toothbrushes at each other's places, foreplay's out the window.
- 进出自由 想睡就睡 好得很 - 可不止五个月
I'm in, I'm out, I'm sleeping, it's great. It's more than five months.
你们以前交往过 那段时间也算
You guys dated before; that time counts.
时间不会自动清零
The clock doesn't reset to zero.
之前只是暂停 现在又继续了
It un-pauses from where you left off.
不可能 时间清零了
No way, no way, the clock resets.
等会 你们俩就有这爱好是吧
Wait, so this is what you guys do?
请别的情侣一起吃饭 然后对他们 评头论足 显得你们多优越似的
You invite other couples over for dinner to judge them and feel superior?
成熟点 Ted
Oh, grow up, Ted,
这是自古以来每对情侣都有的通病
that's why any couple invites anyone over ever.
两杯苏格兰威士忌 纯的
Two Scotches, both neat,
再来点坚果 这家伙刚丢了一对儿(坚果=蛋蛋)
and if you've got some, uh, nuts, this guy lost a couple.
一切为了组织
Take the hit, just take the hit.
他这是在求救呢
Okay, this is a cry for help.
今晚我们请Barney过来吃饭好吗
Can we invite Barney over for dinner tonight?
可是我本来要给你做顿特别大餐
But I was going to make you a special meal to celebrate
庆祝我的节目提名本地媒体大奖呢
my show getting nominated for a Local Area Media Award.
哦对 忘说了 Nick在有线台做了一档烹饪节目
Oh, yeah, I forgot to mention, Nick had a cable access cooking show.
Nick Podarutti大厨均选用本地出产的新鲜食材
Chef Nick Podarutti uses all fresh, locally grown ingredients,
但千万不要以为他就不是坏男孩哦
but don't think for a second that means he's not a bad boy.
她的动力来自玉米
She runs on corn.
* Nick大厨 *
铀?Nick the Bad Boy
* 坏男孩 *
铀?Chef...
我要请他过来吃晚饭
I'm gonna invite him over for dinner.
那好吧 不过他得有票
Okay, fine, but you'd better make sure he has a ticket.
因为"请登上美食列车"
'Cause it's all aboard the Chow-Chow Train!
亲爱的 我知道要给美食节目
Honey, I know it's hard coming up
想个有代表性的广告语挺难的
with a signature cooking catchphrase,
但这个真不行
but I don't think that's it.
我知道 可是什么能比得过"砰!"呢
I know, but how do you compete with "Bam!"?
这一字可是金不换啊
It just says it all.
嘿 你回来啦
Hey, you.
嘿 我能问你点事吗
Hey, can I ask you something?
Lily和Marshall觉得
Um, Lily and Marshall think
你在暗示我想要更进一步 但我没有理解
I'm missing all these hints you're dropping that you want a deeper commitment.
如果是这样 你会直说的 对吧
I mean, you'd just come right out and tell me, right?
当然了
Totally.
- 我肯定会直接一点告诉你的 - 谢谢
I- I think I can be a little bit more direct than that. Thank you.
哦对 我今天打扫了我的公寓
Oh, hey, I was cleaning my apartment today
然后发现了这个
and I dug this up.
我要留著这件婚纱吗 还是你觉得
Should I keep this wedding dress, or do you think
我这辈子就再用不著了
I'll never, ever need it again?
- 所以Lily和Marshall是对的 - 当然啊
So Lily and Marshall were right? Of course they're right.
一个女孩穿著婚纱钻进你的车
When a girl jumps in your car in a wedding dress,
难道你还惊讶她想要结婚吗
you can't act surprised to find out she wants to get married.
再说了 我们以前交往过 那段时间也算
Besides, we dated before, and that time counts.
之前是暂停 现在继续
We just hit pause on the clock.
很多智慧的人都觉得时间清零了
See, a lot of really smart people would argue the clock resets.
- 就是暂停 大家都懂的 - Barney有点晚了
It un-pauses, everybody knows that. You know, Barney's a little late.
希望他没事
I hope he's okay.
没事的 而且我根本不觉得他在求救
Ah, he's fine, and I still don't think he's crying out for help.
这个...
Well...
抱歉我们迟到了 刚从裁缝那回来
Sorry we're late. We just came from the tailor.
流浪兄弟选不定领带 所以我就都买了
Brover couldn't settle on a tie, so I just bought them all.
看这小脸 不忍拒绝啊
You say no to that face.
你不能完全确定我们的事 肯定是有原因的 Ted
There's a reason that you're not a hundred percent in this with me, Ted.
我们之间有阻碍
Something's holding us back.
是什么呢
Well, what is it?
咱都知道我不擅长把握线索 说到这个
I think we've established I'm not great at picking up on clues- well, in this situation.
我小时候可是个小侦探哦
As a kid, I was known as a bit of a detective.
我朋友的牙架丢了
In fact, when my friend's retainer went missing,
Mosby男孩接手案件 结果它在...
the Mosby Boys were put on the case, and it was...
在垃圾箱里 Mosby男孩就是你和你妹
The retainer was in the garbage. The Mosby Boys were you, your sister,
还有你自以为被你驯服的小松鼠
and a neighborhood squirrel you thought you had tamed.
真想不到松鼠福尔摩斯会那么让我们失望
I can't believe Squirrel-lock Holmes turned on us like that.
- 训练了八周呢 - 你知道我怎么知道的么 Ted
Eight weeks of training down the drain. You know how I know that, Ted?
因为六年前 在我们决定加深t解时说过的
Because we covered it in the "getting to know you" part of the relationship six years ago.
六年
Six years.
那到底是什么在阻碍我们
Then... what's holding us back?
去找Mosby男孩 Ted 破案了告诉我
Call in the Mosby Boys, Ted, let me know if they crack the case.
伙计们
Guys,
流浪兄弟不只是我有过最棒的兄弟
Brover is not only the best bro I've ever had,
他还很会和姑娘们打交道呢
he's amazing with the ladies.
不好意思 你不觉得利用一只狗去泡钮挺悲哀的吗
I'm sorry, don't you think it's a little pathetic to use a dog to pick up chicks?
先生 泡钮搭档的关系是双向的
Sir, wingmanship is a two-way street.
如果流浪兄弟看上了谁 我也愿为组织牺牲
If Brover meets a cutie, I'll take the hit
陪她的肥钮朋友聊天
and chat up the chubby lady friend.
有时会装成恶棍
Sometimes I'll be the jerk...
让流浪兄弟英雄救美
...so Brover can swoop in and be the hero.
和任何一个称职的泡钮搭档一样
And like any good wingman,
我会保持理智的头脑
I gather as much intel as I can right up front.
- 你的狗几岁了 - 五岁
How old's your dog? She's five. Oh.
- 按狗的寿命来说是多大 - 大概35岁
What's that in dog years? Like, 35.
拜拜了您哪
We're done here.
你们说得对
Well, you were right.
Victoria说我们之间有阻碍 可我想不出是什么
Victoria says something's holding us back, and I don't have any idea what it is.
有什么好想法吗 Oprah
Any brilliant insights, Oprah?
Steadman (Oprah的前男友)
Steadman?
你咋不说Gayle (曾被传和Oprah是同性恋人)
Um, try Gayle.
Marshall 交给你 你已经准备好了
Marshall, I want you to take this one. You're ready.
不好说啊
Oh, I don't know.
不过我脑子里确实有个声音在说些什么
Although I do hear this little voice in the back of my head trying to tell me something.
那是你内心的女神
That's your inner goddess.
倾听她 引导她
Listen to her, channel her.
如果Victoria对你来说
If Victoria quenches your
就像炎热七月里的一杯甜茶
thirst like a tall glass
那样解渴
of sweet tea on a hot July day...
Marshall 你女神咋南方口音
Marshall, why is she Southern?
别害他中断连接
Don't let him break the connection.
你就必须对她诚实以待
...well, you got to make an honest woman out of her.
我走了
Okay, I'm leaving.
但是 但是
But, but,
如果你做不到 小蜜糖
if not, well, then, sugar...
你就应该让那只小夜莺
...you got to let that nightingale
展开双臂 振翅高飞
spread her wings and soar
通向属于她的美好明天
to her own beautiful tomorrow.
出徒了
Testify.
你们俩讨厌死了
You guys are the worst.
我在哪里
Where am I?
抱歉
Sorry.
我是Barney
Uh, go for Barney.
我知道
I see.
完全明白
Totally understood.
我会的 很好
I'll do that. Great.
谢谢
Thank you.
是流浪兄弟的主人
That was Brover's owner.
她出城的时候 他从狗窝里跑了出来
I guess, while she was out of town, he ran away from his kennel,
现在她回来了 我得把他还回去
and now that she's back, I have to return him.
- Barney 我很遗憾 - 没事
Oh, Barney, I'm so sorry. Oh, it's all good.
我先失陪一下
Um, excuse me for one moment.
Barney
Barney.
别拦我
No, no. No, no!
Victoria
Victoria.
- 你愿意嫁给我吗 - 当然愿意
Will you marry me? Yes, of course.
只有一件事
There's just one thing.
任何事都可以 你尽管说
Anything. You name it.
你不能再和Robin作朋友
You can't be friends with Robin.
如果我还和Robin作朋友 你就不愿意嫁给我吗
You won't marry me if I'm still friends with Robin?
等等 难道她就是我们的阻碍?
Wait. She's the thing that's been holding us back?
过去的事情太复杂了
There-There's just too much history there.
我们第一次分手就是因为Robin Robin是我们的路障
I mean, Robin's the reason that we broke up the first time around. Robin's our roadblock.
Robin是黑暗的深洞 会葬送我们的爱情
Robin's the deep, dark pit where our relationship goes to die.
不过她是好姑娘 优秀青年
But nicest girl in the world. Salt of the earth.
可她现在和Nick在一起了啊
But she's with Nick now.
尽管他的烹饪节目里Q是些奇奇怪怪的广告词
I mean, sure, his cooking show is lousy with awkward catchphrase attempts.
我的妈呀 来点点心吗
Oh, my gosh, who's ready to nosh?
谁对美食垂涎欲滴啊 (pop a chub也指勃起)
Who's popping a chub for some grub?
我向被"垂涎欲滴"冒犯到的观众朋友表示真诚的歉意
I offer my deepest apologies to anyone who was offended by my "popping a chub" remark.
我会更加努力 下不为例
I can and will do better. Won't happen again.
谁想吃我的肉啊
And now who's ready to eat my meat?
有没有搞错
Oh, come on.
可Robin跟Nick在一起很幸福 我和你在一起也很幸福
But Robin's happy with Nick, and I'm happy with you.
你看 我刚刚都跟你求婚了
Look, I, I just asked you to be my wife.
这还不能证明我跟Robin之间没什么吗
Isn't that proof there's nothing between me and Robin?
也许今天是没有 可明天呢
Well, maybe today there isn't, but what about tomorrow?
或者下星期 又或者15年后呢
Or next week or 15 years from now?
我会一直感到不安
I'll always be wondering.
我并不想对你说出
I never wanted to be that girl who says
"Robin还是我"这种话
it's Robin or it's me,
可是...
but, well...
选Robin还是选你
It's Robin or it's you.
你是个很棒的泡钮搭档
You've been a hell of a wingman.
尽管我觉得你自己舔自己挺f心的
And even though I think it's kind of gross when you pleasure yourself orally,
但我确实是大开眼界
don't ever think that means I'm not impressed.
你说把流浪兄弟送回去 Barney不会有事吧
do you think that Barney's gonna be okay bringing Brover back?
当然不会
Yeah, he'll be fine.
这不仅仅是一种能给自己口交的能力
It's not just the ability to go to town on yourself,
更是人生一大乐事啊
but you do it with such joie de vivre.
我觉得我应该陪他去
I really think that I should go with him.
不行 你得吃这些薄煎饼 都烤好了
No, but you got to eat these cr锚pes as soon as they're flamb茅ed.
保证让你胃口大开哦
They're gonna be bon appe-sweet!
- 不好 - 奶奶的
No. Damn.
等我回来咱们一起想
We'll work on it when I get back.
不用 我懂了 我为这些忙活了一整晚
No, I get it. You know, I only spent all night working on these,
可是呢 Barney更重要
but, hey, Barney's more important.
- Nick - 没事 去吧
Nick... It's fine. Go.
总之呢 这也没什么大不了的
Anyway, let's not make a big deal of it.
我们不过是一起玩了几天 找了点乐子
We hung out for a few days, had some fun...
算什么呀
No big woof.
我不会忘记你的
I'LL NEVER FORGET YOU
没有你我可咋办
I don't know who I am without you.
真荒唐
This is crazy.
Victoria对Robin这事也太不讲理了
Victoria is being completely unreasonable about Robin,
我的响指姐妹支援两句
and my snap sister is gonna back me up.
我再来一次
I say again...
我有点能理解Victoria
I kind of see Victoria's point.
- 软糖小姐没听清楚 - Ted和Robin有过太多过去
Come again for Ms. Fudge? Ted and Robin have so much history.
没错 是过去 早都翻篇儿了
Exactly. History. Ancient history.
Ted 今年你还对她说过"我爱你"呢
Ted, you said "I love you" to her earlier this year.
我并不是说她做得对 但我能理解
I'm not saying this is fair, but I get it.
我完全不理解
I didn't get that at all.
我内心的女神怎么弃我而去了呢
How could my inner goddess be so far off?
以后你会懂的 Oprah的境界也不是一天修炼成的啊
Oh, you'll get there, honey. Oprah wasn't built in a day.
- 嗯 - 怎么了
Uh-oh. What?
我稍微淘气了一下
I kind of went rogue.
如果你真的想要孩子 别再吃药就好了
Look, if you really want to have a baby, just stop taking the pill.
你们俩三年前的春假上过床
You guys slept together at spring break three years ago.
这里肯定有事儿
That means something.
喜欢电视插曲 超级购物狂
Loves show tunes, total shopaholic,
不总缠著你求爱爱
not always pestering you for sex?
Clifford听起来可以托付终生
Um, Clifford sounds like a keeper.
Marshall 你这些建议都烂透了
Marshall, all of that advice was terrible.
那也比你建议Ted和Robin不要再作朋友了强
Not as terrible as you saying that Ted and Robin should stop being friends.
我没说他们应该这样 那就太糟糕了
I'm not saying they should. It would be horrible.
可如果Ted真的想和Victoria在一起...
But if Ted really wants to be with Victoria...
Ted 告诉她
Ted, tell her
你不会和Robin绝交的
that you're not gonna stop being friends with Robin.
我无法想像没有Robin的人生
I can't imagine life without Robin.
可她不可能爱上我
But she'll never be in love with me.
不可能作我的妻子
She'll never be my wife.
不可能和我一起变老
She'll never be the person I grow old with.
Victoria...
Victoria可能可以
Victoria could be.
你说的跟我想的是一个意思吗
Are you saying what I think you're saying?
准备好说再见了吗
You ready to say good-bye?
谢谢你陪我来
Thanks for coming with me.
我把我的狗送走时 你也是这样对我的 记得吗
Oh, well, you did the same for me back when I had to give away all my dogs. Remember?
对啊 我们开车去你阿姨家的农场
Oh, yeah, we drove to your aunt's farm upstate.
她人很好
She was awesome.
我喜欢她聪慧成熟淡定的
Yeah. I love how she was this wise, old, chilled out,
蕾丝边农场主气质
lesbian farmer.
不不不 她不是蕾丝边 她也不是农场主
No, no, no. She's not a lesbian. Nor does she farm them.
跟她同住的女人只是她一个特别的朋友Maureen
No, that woman she lives with, that's just her special friend Maureen.
她们一起住了...
They've lived together for...
这肯定会很难过的
Oh, this is gonna be tough.
流浪兄弟真是最棒的泡钮搭档
Brover really was the best wingman ever.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
非常感谢你
Thank you so much for bringing
- 把小雨点送回来 - 小雨点
Mr. Sprinkles back. Mr. Sprinkles...
真是个好听的狗狗名字
is a great name for a dog.
妈咪好想你 真的好想啊
Mommy missed you so much. Yes, she did.
这对情侣有好好照顾你吗
Did this nice couple take care of you?
太好笑了
That's a laugh. Ha.
兄弟
Big bro.
我得撤了 嗯 走了
I got to split. Yeah, I got to,
我得回农场去
I got to head back to the farm...
我和我的特别朋友Maureen住在一起
where I live with my special friend Maureen.
我现在意识到她其实是我的同性伴侣
Whom I now realize is my lesbian life partner.
惊讶吧
Surprise.
好了
Okay. All right.
那么
So...
你要不要喝一杯
would you like a drink?
最棒的泡钮搭档
Best wingman ever.
这是什么 我还以为你在生我的气
What's all this? I thought you were mad at me.
本来是在生气 但后来我意识到
I was... but then I realized
我必须要接受你有亲密的男性朋友这个事实
I just have to accept that you have close guy friends.
但我可不希望这习惯成自然
I mean, I don't want it becoming a habit
大半夜的把你叫走什么的
that they steal you away from me in the middle of the night.
但是
But...
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
Ted想见我
Oh, Ted needs to see me.
- 我的老天 你这个女人 - 不是你想的那样 他只是想嘿休而已
Oh, for the love of God, woman. Oh, it's not what you think. He just wants to have sex.
开玩笑啦
Kidding.
只要动动手就好 还是开玩笑啦
Just a little hand stuff. Ha. Kidding again.
Ted对胸部最著迷 我怎么就停不住了
Ted's more of a boob man. I seriously can't stop.
他有什么事
What does he want? Um...
不知道 可他说是急事
I don't know, but he says it's urgent.
对不起 再让我被夺走一下下吧
I'm so sorry. Just one more little steal-away.
只要你还会回来
Just as long as he gives you back.
谢谢
Thanks.
NO ...
那么
So...
你还好吗
are you okay?
到底是什么急事 都不能等到明天
What is this big, urgent thing that couldn't wait till tomorrow?
我有件事要告诉你
There's something I have to tell you.
这件事我常常在想
I've thought about this a ton,
而且
and, um...
我本来不希望说起这件事
I was hoping it wouldn't come to this,
但是
but...
我不爱Robin
I'm not in love with Robin, um,
但她就像是我的家人
but she's like family to me, and, uh...
我不能结束这一切
I can't end that.
所以
So...
你可以接受吗
can you accept that?
我真的希望有一天你能得到她
I really hope you get her some day.
嘿 伙计们
Hey, guys.
昨晚Ted打给我让我去酒吧 说有急事
So, last night Ted calls me out to the bar to talk about something urgent.
你们猜是什么
Guess what it was.
他想写一部青少年系列推理小说
He wants to write a series of young adult mystery novels
叫"Mosby男孩"
called The Mosby Boys.
你干嘛非要告诉我这个
Why did you need to tell me that?
你在媒体界嘛 人面广大
You work in the media. You know people.
好吧 首先无视掉Mosby白痴 著重写会破案的松鼠
Okay, well, first of all, lose the Mosby nerds and focus on that crime-solving squirrel.
那家伙太棒了
That guy is gold. Yeah.
第二 下次你再想大半夜的商谈要事
And secondly, next time you have a big idea late at night,
拜托去烦你的女朋友
please bug your girlfriend about it.
其实 我和Victoria分手了
Uh, actually... Victoria and I broke up.
天啊
Oh, my God.
为什么 发生什么事了
Why, what, what happened?
我们只是 想要不同的生活
We just, you know, wanted different things.
真遗憾 兄弟
I'm so sorry, buddy.
但往好处想 如果Robin知道你是因为她
But, bright side... Robin is gonna be so touched
才和Victoria分手 一定会很感动的
when she hears you ended things with Victoria because of her.
不能让她知道 答应我 永远不会让Robin知道这件事
She can never know. Promise me Robin will never find out.
- 我不明白 - 答应我
I don't understand. Promise.
答应你
Promise. Promise.
当然 Robin还是知道了
Of course, Robin did find out.
我们以后再讲
But we'll get to that.
兄弟 救我
BRO HELP
有个疯婆子说我把她肚子搞大了
SOME ...UP
你还是个爷们儿啊
So you do have balls?
快跑
Run!